JUBRIL GBOLAHAN ADIGUN

Researcher, PhD Candidate of Computer Science

Innsbruck, 6020, Austria

adjubril@hotmail.com; ask4jubad@yahoo.com

+4368864199319; +37256187770

PROFILE

I have 5 years combined low-to-mid level experience in engineering and business with exposure to Programming, Information Technology and Accounting and working with NGOs. My interests include but are not limited to Internet of Things, Development of High-Assured Autonomous Systems, and Computer Vision in both domestic and industrial contexts, Sustainability and Inequality reduction.

LINKS

<u>Linkedin</u> <u>Bitbucket</u> <u>Personality Assessment</u> <u>Writing</u> <u>Instagram</u> <u>Facebook</u> <u>Twitter</u>

EDUCATION

PhD Computer Science, University of Innsbruck, Innsbruck

FEBRUAURY 2021

(In view)

Master of Science in Engineering, Software Engineering, University of Tartu (joint program with Tallinn University of Technology), Tartu

SEPTEMBER 2018 - AUGUST 2020

Embedded and Real time systems Specialization

Bachelor of Engineering, Electrical and Electronics Engineering, University of Ilorin, Ilorin

NOVEMBER 2010 - AUGUST 2015

Computer and Control Specialization

Diploma in Accounting and Business, ACCA

JANUARY 2018 - JANUARY 2018

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Research Assistant, University of Innsbruck, Innsbruck

FEBRUARY 2021 - PRESENT

- Engaged with the Quality Engineering Group of the Department of Computer Science working on continuous collaborative quality assurance in IT management, software engineering and systems operation evaluated in industrial case studies.
- My research focuses on testing of IoT systems and collaborative AI systems, developing innovative test-beds, running simulations for autonomous systems and exploring metamorphic relations in a range of applications.

Test Engineer, Ericsson Eesti AS, Tallinn

JULY 2019 - JANUARY 2021

 I was responsible for ensuring continuous yield sustainability at high performance and achieved yield up to a high of 96%

- I provided technical support during New Product Introduction, Transfer Product Introduction
- I led test fault analysis during radio production providing strategic technical leadership for test technicians and insights for business leaders.
- I actively participated in SW & HW installation, verification and maintenance steering continuous analysis and requirements handling.

Test Engineer Trainee, Ericsson Eesti AS, Tallinn

MARCH 2019 - JULY 2019

- I functioned in the capacity of second line support for radio production driving and HW&SW implementation for classic radios.
- I was successfully engaged on 3 families of product, assisting team members and actively delivering reports.

Experienced Audit Analyst, KPMG Professional Services Limited, Victoria Island, Lagos

FEBRUARY 2018 - AUGUST 2018

- I successfully completed an audit from start to finish of an A+ rated (GCR) money market fund in Nigeria fund in 2018
- I co-audited many businesses within the financial sector: banks, pension houses, investments, trustees, funds and properties.
- I provided technical know-how to junior team members working together with IT Analysts in understanding of business processes and internal control measures.

Audit Analyst, KPMG Professional Services Limited, Victoria Island, Lagos

NOVEMBER 2016 - JANUARY 2018

• Imbibed best Generally Acceptable Accounting Principles - GAAP practices to deliver quality audit function to businesses by preparing financial accounts, and reviewing internal controls for various entities within the financial services industry in Nigeria.

Laser Survey Engineer, Ariosh Limited, Victoria Island, Lagos

MAY 2016 - NOVEMBER 2016

- Underwent Deep Water Safety and Tropical Basic Offshore Safety Induction and Escape Techniques
- 3D As-built Laser Data Documentation

Management Trainee Engineer, Ariosh Limited, Victoria Island, Lagos

OCTOBER 2015 - NOVEMBER 2016

- Steered the development of a weekly bulletin on safety for the company
- Drew up graphic designs (Stamps, Profiles, Templates and Reports) facilitating the development of the company's 2015 annual report.
- I collaborated on the groundwork for the interface design of a Timesheet Manager
- I orchestrated technical documents used internally and for presentations and contract bidding as tenders and response to Invitation to Tenders (ITT)

OTHER ENGAGEMENTS

Partner - EDUOpinions (Freelance), Remote

SEPTEMBER 2019 — PRESENT

 Content creator collecting reviews from university students around the world to assist future students make informed decisions about attending choice schools

Intern, Juststandout Limited, Lekki, Lagos

SEPTEMBER 2013 - FEBRUARY 2014

- Led project teams to business and personal clients during Installation of Kilowatts Inverters, electronic and electrical appliances
- Provided offline and field support to company clients
- Garnered more hands-on experience on machining processes
- Participated in exhibitions to promote company activities
- Did repairs and rework of damaged client appliances

SKILLS

Effective Time Management Adaptability

Communication Skills Ability to Work in a Team

JavaScript Python

C ROS+Autoware

F# Elixir

Microsoft Office Programming

Autonomous vehicle Embedded Systems

UML/CTL BeamNG.research

Machine Learning Learning Analytics

Matlab & Simulink Design Thinking

Anti-Debating HTML/CSS/JavaScript

Adobe InDesign Adobe XD

Corel Draw Enterprise Architecture

UPPAAL Magic Draw
Arduino Raspberry Pi

Scientific Computing Linux

Windows Creative Thinking

Cognitive Flexibility Service Orientation

Emotional Intelligence AutoCAD

PDMS

EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Research Director, UYSG Lagos Chapter, Lagos

DECEMBER 2020 - PRESENT

Lead the research team of UYSG Lagos Chapter in carrying out well-founded research to help the organization better position itself as a changemaker with valuable impact in both its immediate constituency and at a global scale.

Projects

- Food System Summit Dialogues 2021 (In view)
- Lagos Ocean Cleanup (In collaboration with TrashUsers with support from LAWMA In view)

Program Director Lead, CareerEdu, Ilorin, Kwara

JULY 2020 - PRESENT

• I lead a combined team of 11 Program Directors and Advocacy Managers for the CareerEdu group driving partnerships, operational development and policies

Projects

- International Day of Persons with Disabilities (IDPD 2020)
- CareerEdu Signing Championship (2021)
- World Down Syndrome Day (In view)

https://careereduglobal.org/

Volunteer - Online Mentoring Session, Latitude 59, Virtual (Tallinn, Estonia)

AUGUST 2020 - AUGUST 2020

I facilitated online mentoring sessions on zoom during the dates of the events by ensuring that mentors and participants are moderated during the mentoring sessions.

Sessions

- Scaleup operating models: What are the best scaleups in Europe doing right
- Market entry: Brazil
- How to stalk growth through a crisis

Campus Director, Hult Prize University of Tartu, Tartu

SEPTEMBER 2019 - JUNE 2020

• Under the auspice of the global Hult Prize Foundation, I recruited and successfully led a team of 9 members from different works of life and levels of academic ratification to organize the first ever Hult Prize On Campus Challenge at the University of Tartu.

http://www.hultprize.org/

Participant, Codemotion, Online Conference

MAY 2020 - MAY 2020

• Attended the "Shaping the future with Deep Learning" online conference

https://cutt.ly/codemotion_badge

Volunteer, Startup Day 2020, Tartu

JANUARY 2020 — JANUARY 2020

• This was my second year volunteering at the 2-day main events playing host to more than 4000 attendees from all over the world. The event plays host to tech leaders, startups, business giants, academicians and researchers from different areas of endeavor.

https://www.startupday.ee/

Participant, CEE Fintech Leaders Forum, Warsaw

JANUARY 2020 — JANUARY 2020

• Diploma for Outstanding Solution - I was part of the Open Banking and Big data team that won the award of outstanding performance for our proposition of a blockchain solution for the health sector at the Leslaw A. Paga Foundation CEE Fintech Leaders Forum

Attendee, Slush Helsinki 2018, Helsinki

DECEMBER 2018 - DECEMBER 2018

• A student-driven movement for technology, business and entrepreneurship

https://www.slush.org/

Volunteer, Changemakers Summit 2019, Tartu

JUNE 2019 - JUNE 2019

https://changemakerssummit.org/

Volunteer, Startup Day 2019, Tartu

JANUARY 2019 - JANUARY 2019

 Volunteered in the wardrobe team taking care of attendees' properties and clothes. This involved strategic dual numbering of items to match individuals with their belongings. This was also a good platform to interact and offer good reception to the participants by putting up a smile and attending to fringe needs.

https://www.startupday.ee/

Participant and Alumnus, DD Academy, Tartu

OCTOBER 2018 - MAY 2019

• DD Academy is a youth empowerment program setup to create new institutions and change obsolete ones with the goal of enabling unchanging humans to adapt to the ever-changing environment

https://ddacademy.net/

LANGUAGES

Yoruba	English	
Arabic	Chinese	
French	German	

HOBBIES

Programming, Volunteering, Cartoons, Animation, Family times, Stand up comedy, Writing, Graphics design, Copy editing.

COURSES AND TRAININGS

Disability Awareness and Support, University of Pittsburgh (Coursera)

MARCH 2021

Jobberman Soft-Skills Training, Jobberman

MARCH 2021 - MARCH 2021

Motion Planning for Self-Driving Cars, University of Toronto (Coursera)

JUNE 2020 - PRESENT

The quickstart guide to YouTube, YouTube Creator Academy

APRIL 2020 - APRIL 2020

Intel® Edge AI Scholarship Foundation Course, Udacity Nanodegree Program

FEBRUARY 2020 - PRESENT

Model-based Development of Autonomous Systems (Summer School)), Åbo Akademi University

JULY 2019 - JULY 2019

Fire Safety Risk Assessment (License issued by Department of Petroleum Resources (DPR) - DPR.00495529/04/14)), Novelle Center

FEBRUARY 2017 - FEBRUARY 2017

Tropical Basic Offshore Safety Induction and Escape Technique (TBOSIET) (License issued by TÜV InterCert - Group of TÜV Saarland - T1650658793), Tollman Allied Services Company Limited

JUNE 2016 - JUNE 2020

UK HSE Level I,II & III (Issued by British International Safety Organisation), Novelle Center FEBRUARY 2017 — FEBRUARY 2017

ESSCaSS 2019 (18th Estonian Summer School on Computer and Systems Science), University of Tartu AUGUST 2019 — AUGUST 2019

General Health, Safety and Environmental Awareness, British Safety Council

SEPTEMBER 2016 - SEPTEMBER 2016

MEMBERSHIP

Nigerian Society of Engineers (NSE) - Graduate Member

National Society of High School Scholar (NSHSS) - Fellow

Leslaw A. Paga Foundation - Alumnus

THESES

Master's thesis, Tallinn

AUGUST 2020

Ground truth data for Object Detection in Autonomous Vehicle from a Driving Simulator

Bachelor's thesis, Ilorin

JUNE 2020

A Study of GSM Propagation on Unilorin Campus Using Walfisch-Ikegami Model